Jericho Mata

San Jose, CA | 201.423.2256 | jericho.mata9@gmail.com | Portfolio | LinkedIn | Github

SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS

3+ years of technical experience with successful Full-Stack deployments using React, Javascript, and Python. Innovative, passionate, analytical, and looking to hone my skills in Web Development as well as grow within a company whose values I align with. Driven to collaborate and to learn more about product development process.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- **Programming Languages:** JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, Python, C, C++, C#, Objective C, SQL, JSON, MATLAB, RUST. Haskell
- Libraries/ Frameworks & Tools: React, Node.js, Express, Git, Firebase, Flask, Django, Heroku, NumPy

SOFTWARE PROJECTS

BudgetBetter | HackCWRU 2022: FinTech Track, 1st Place

DevPost | Live | Github

Mar 2022 - Sep 2022

Python, Flask, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, React, Node, Docker, Heroku

- Money management platform where users input transactions, set goals, and view graphical budgeting trends
- Implemented **Plaid's API** calls to retrieve banking data from over 2000 institutions then categorized transactions into 4 dynamic webpages using **JavaScript** and deployed on **Heroku**
- Integrated **React** and **Flask** to store transactional data for each user into dedicated database to improve **UI** and to increase page load speeds by **15**%
- Utilized JSON Web Tokens to authenticate users when retrieving API data to protect users' transactions history

Music Genre Prediction and Web Application

Demo Github

Python, Flask, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, React, KNN, SVM

Apr 2022 - Jun 2022

- Big data models connected to web application that identifies non-overlapping music genre for classification
- Successfully created Neural Network and Multi-Layer Perceptron model using Python that yielded 86% accuracy in determining correct music genre
- Led web application team of 3 to build frontend using **React** and backend using **Flask** that receives audio files, extracts features, runs model, and sends prediction

Vestibular Migraine Evaluation Tool

Github

Python, Deep Learning, NLP

Jul 2022 - Present

- A.I. approach to help doctors evaluate patient diagnosis severity using data from social media platforms
- Scraped and extracted over **120,000** Twitter tweets with Vestibular Migraine symptoms using **Python**
- Managed team of 3 developers to extract relevant data from Twitter using natural language processing, resulting in increased accuracy of patient diagnosis by 11%

WORK EXPERIENCE

Freestand | Remote | Full-Stack Web Developer Intern

May 2021 - Sep 2021

- Integrated Cloud Firebase storage, allowing users to directly upload up to 20 .jpg, .png, or.mp4 files to their
 own profile pages and drag files into respective subsections which improved UI/UX
- Designed & implemented full stack CRUD web application to teach financial literacy using React and Node.js

Green Science Games | Davis, CA | *Game Developer Intern*

Feb 2020 - Apr 2020

- Created 2D game based on Plants vs. Zombies using **Unity** and **C#** which supported learning of K-6 students'
- Automated customer reporting system in handling issues related to live-image captures and dynamic image renders by developing internal ticketing **query** system within game interface

Finesse Apparel | Sacramento, CA | Website Designer (UI/ UX)

Oct 2018 - Jun 2019

- Created brand and took on multiple roles including logo design using Adobe Illustrator, development of
 website, and delivered content across social media platforms increasing web traffic and sales by 33%
- Oversaw team of 4 developers, acting as project manager for platform transition and developed concepts, target audience, requirements, deadlines, and budgets

EDUCATION

University of California, Davis

Davis, CA